# **GIDI** MEIR **MORRIS**

## Software Developer & Engineering Manager

cv@gidi.io

London, UK

gidi.io

github.com/gmmorris

in uk.linkedin.com/in/ gidimorris

## Primary Toolset

## **Methodologies & Catalytic** Skills

Individuals and Interactions over **Processes and Tools** Extreme Programming, Scrum Pair & Mob Programming Mentorship & Collaboration

## **DevOps Practices**

Continuous integration, delivery & feedback

Monitoring, Alerting & Observability

#### **Technical Domain**

Typescript, Node.js Java 8+

Rust 2018+, Actix-web

CSS, SASS & their ilk

HTML, The DOM & Web APIs

Rxjs, React, Remix

**Functional & Reactive programming** 

Reactive system design

AWS, GCP, Terraform & Immutable Infrastructure

Elasticsearch & the ELK Stack

Test Driven Development

Automated Testing (browser & blackbox)

### Open Source Projects on github.com/gmmorris

Over the past 20 years I have been involved in several open-source projects. In addition to releasing my own projects I have contributed years to several the community projects such as Babel, jQuery, highlights.js, and mootools

## Profile

I'm an accomplished technology leader with a track record of building, leading and nurturing top-performing engineering teams, and delivering products with sustainable efficiency. With over two decades of experience, I've held various technical and managerial roles at different levels. My focus extends beyond technical expertise to include agile practices, team dynamics, continuous improvement, and mentorship, all vital for successful product delivery. I'm dedicated not only to delivering high-quality work but also to making a positive impact on my community and industry, driving positive social and environmental change.

## Work Experience

#### NatureBound Co-Founder & CTO

2022 - 2023

As Co-Founder of a climate change focused venture aimed at reducing emissions and biodiversity-loss, I raised £160k in equity and grant funding.

Led customer discovery across several sectors, culminating in a POC Biodiversity Observability platform, targetting two of our target markets. Secured multiple partnerships and collaborations with biodiversity monitoring companies, data providers, and domain experts.

Learned a lot about climate change, biodiversity, entrepreneurship and myself.

#### Elastic Senior Engineering Manager (Alerting & ResponseOps Team Lead)

2020 - 2022

I successfully led the iterative engineering initiative to scale Elastic's alerting offering from a limited beta to a fully enterprise-ready General Availability product. This involved expanding the Elastic Alerting project from a small engineering team to a robust 20+ person organisation. I led the recruitment and onboarding of engineers into multiple teams and provided guidance to area leads as they adapted to a new agile process in a distributed work environment.

I introduced a cross-departmental structure to enhance collaboration and prioritisation, facilitating alignment between the Platform, Security, and Observability product teams by enabling them to understand each other's priorities, constraints, and incentives. Additionally, I conducted a series of organization-wide learning and development training sessions focusing on Catalytic Skills, which encompassed essential communication skills and a growth mindset required for high-performing teams to collaborate and function effectively.

Led the hiring process to identify a suitable replacement for my role as I departed the company to focus on climate change.

#### Elastic **Principal Software Engineer**

2019 - 2020

Significantly improved the scalability of the Elastic Alerting framework powering our Security and Observability products, growing rule capacity 100x per-node throughout Kibana's distributed Task Manager.

#### Unruly Senior Software Developer (Supply-Side Team Lead)

2016 - 2019

**Engineering management** of an Extreme Programming (XP) development team of over 10 members, providing mentorship and practical technical guidance. As the owner of the Programmatic Demand business strand, I led the prioritisation and oversaw the research and delivery of business value in an efficient and sustainable manner. Led the R&D efforts behind the introduction of the Unruly Ad Exchange, a multi-region distributed system handling thousands of ad requests per second, and our Supply Side Platform, a web application developed using React and Redux. Operating within an XP environment, which emphasises agile methodologies, Pair and Mob Programming, Collective Ownership, and Merciless Refactoring, I fostered collaboration, self-organization, and a variety of catalytic skills throughout all aspects of product delivery. Assumed the role of stewarding the Product Development Diversity & Inclusivity group, and as Unruly's first Nomad, I provided technical leadership across all development teams.

## Education

Officer Candidate School (IDF) 2006

## Software Development Management

Professional diploma

Intensive 6 month course qualification as a Military Officer, covering Leadership and Team Building, with a specialisation in Project Management and Software Development Processes.

Mamram (IDF)

2003

## Software Development Bootcamp

**Professional diploma** 

Intensive 6 month course covering development and software design principles, actual work experience in a variety of development environments such as C, C++, ASP & Javascript, Java, Perl, SQL and PL-SQL and working environments such as Windows and Unix.

Kvutzat Yavne High School 2002

### **High School Diploma**

Computer Science major

## Who Am I Really?

I grew up on an agricultural village in Israel, but it was in Tel Aviv that I truly discovered myself. Alongside my tech pursuits, I've made a name for myself as a successful photographer, showcasing work in Israel and London, handling commercial projects for clients in the Israeli entertainment participating sector, and prominent art fairs. Additionally, I'm an avid martial artist, currently holding a 2nd Master grade in Wing Tsun Kung Fu, and a dedicated rock climber. Beyond interests, I'm an commentator on political theological matters, and in 2014, I was honored as one of Quora's Top Writers - they gifted me a custom fleece jacket, which I'm too embarassed to actually wear. My revolves around creation, which might explain why I've found a welcoming home in both the startup and art scenes.

#### Loveholidays Lead Front-End Architect

**Engineering management** of a 7 person development team of *Javascript & Python* developers responsible for the Loveholidays Web Application, providing hands-on technical leadership and prioritisation.

Led the top down rewrite of the entire website (turning\_spaghetti\_into\_lasagne), converting a code base of legacy JS into a modular architecture based on Backbone.js and ES6. Incrementally rearchitected different parts of the site while still providing a stable code base for continued functional development.

### Freelance Engineer R&D and Consulting

2013

Designed and implemented *Front End* solutions, coaching customer R&D teams on their process and approach to engineering. Contracted by several different companies, including ReallyGood, Conduit, Klarna and Cyhawk Ventures.

#### Pluralis Senior Front End Developer

2011 - 2012

As the first employee at an early stage startup (pre round A) I was solely responsible for the design and implemention of the Front End architecture of our A/B testing product.

Using *Backbone.js*, *Underscore*, *jQuery*, *Bootstrap*, *LESS* and vanilla *Javascript*, I created a system for Multivariate A/B testing, an SDK for third-party developers and a web application for the management and execusion of A/B testing competitions.

I built several Javascript libraries, including a library for cross-build module management and a reverse CSS-selector engine for persistable DOM querying.

I supported development of a backend system using Java Spring and AWS. Implemented storage solutions using MongoDB and CouchDB.

#### Metacafe Web Engineer

2011 - 2010

Development of a Web Application using *PHP* and *Javascript* for the Metacafe portal and the site's semantic data layer in a high scale and high traffic web environment.

Designed, implemented and extended infrastructure packages using PHP for Mediawiki, Semantic MediaWiki and an in-house MVC web framework.

Integrated the Metacafe Semantic data layer with the Sesame RDF database.

Implemented caching layers using *Memcached* and *Varnish*, and tuned caching and eviction strategies in *PHP* and *VCL* in a massive scale environment (measuring several millions of request per day). Implemented asynchronous workers using *Gearman* in *PHP* to perform offline processessing and semantic analysis of video content.

#### Military Application System Engineer

2009

Product Management, System Analysis and Oversight over the development of a multimillion dollar *Command & Control* system.

#### Military Team Lead, Army Captain

2006 - 2008

**Engineering management** of two development teams (8 people in total) working on two ASP.Net Web Applications.

Technical design and development of Web Applications and Services in Javascript and C#.

Designed the data layer and integration with both the Oracle 9i and SQLServer databases.

## Military Software Developer

2005 - 2003

Developed an N-Tier ASP.Net web application as part of a four person team. Built both UI and BL components for data display and manipulation using Javascript and C# libraries. Created and took ownership of a department wide position responsible for all UX and design work.

### Freelance Web Designer

2002

Freelance graphic designer, servicing both private clients and companies such as HP's Indigo division.